Mss.B.C55
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Bradley, Stanley E
    See also: Sloan-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research, in:
  - Brandeis University
  - Brent De Silva-Telles, Merces
  - British Schools and Universities Foundation, Inc.
  - Brode, Wallace R
  - Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1963
    Cotzias, George C.; Jackson, G. A.
    I item, 1963 [Box 2] Letter asking Clarke to contribute to the "Festschrift" in honor of Dr. Van Slyke declined by Clarke.
  - Bronk, Detlev Wulf, 1897-
  - Brown, George B
  - Browne, Parker
  - Brynley, David
  - Buchanan, John M
  - Buchanan, Mrs. Susan
  - Budka, Barbara
  - Burdick, C Lalor
  - Business and Professional Women's Foundation
  - C, A
  - Calvert, Robert. Interview with H. T. Clarke, 1953
    1 item, 1953 [Box 2]
    Transcript of an interview of Clarke and the N.Y. Section of the ACS concerning Fordham University Station.
  - Carlson, A J
    Ingle, Dwight J.
  - Carr, Francis H
  - Carver, Mrs. Ruth
  - Chambers, R W
  - Channon, H J
  - Chargaff, Erwin
  - Chase, Robert A
  - Chemical Society (London), 1958
    1 item, 1958 [Box 2]
    Letter to congratulate Clarke's 50th anniversary of membership.
  - Chibnall, A Charles
  - Chick, Harriette
  - Children's Hospital Medical Center (Boston), 1967-1971
    4 items, 1967-1971 [Box 2]
    Notice of appointment of Clarke as consultant in Chemistry for the year 1967-1968.
  - Chilnall, A Charles
  - Christian, Mrs. Marion A
  - Clark, Minnie G
  - Clark, Mansfield(William Mansfield)
    See: Adelphi University
  - Clarke, Mrs. Agnes Helferich, 1930-1935
    c. 40 items, 1930-1935 [Box 2]
    Personal correspondence concerning family affairs.
  - Clarke, Ann Thacher
  - Clarke, Eric Thacher # 1, 1940-1963
    (H.T.C.'s son) 2 files, c. 80 items, 1940-1963 [Box 3]
    100 typed pages of a diary written by Eric Clarke on a U.S. Antartic expedition from the Dept. of the Interior making cosmic ray observations, 1940. 50 letters written from on board ship from Eric to his father of a personal nature.
  - Clarke, Eric Thacher # 2
  - Clarke, Mrs. Frida
    2 files [Box 3]
    Some of Frieda Clarke's awards. Letters of condolence on Freida's death, 1960
  - Clarke, Mrs. Frida --Notes in re: death by unknown persons., 1960
  - Clarke, Hans Thacher, Children, 1924-27
    8 files [Box 3]
    Typescript of a diary concerning Clarke's children 1924-27.
  - Clarke, Hans Thacher,First Annual GoldForb Lecture, 1903-1952, 1953
    Kaempffert, Waldemar; Riddle, Oscar.
    3 copies of Clarke's First Annual Goldforb Lecture given for the Society of Experimental Biology, 1953 in honor of Dr. Goldforb; lists presidents amd secretaries, number of members, number of sections, 1903-1952; also outlines areas of work undertaken by famous biochemists of the period.
  - Clarke, Hans Thacher, First Dakin Memorial Lecture, Adelphia College, 15 May 1953
    Davis, Pierpont V.; Dakin, Zyme. [Box 3]
    First Annual Dakin Memorial Lecture at Aldelphi College, 1952 (?). Typescript written by Clarke for the 50th anniversary of the Journal of Biological Chemistry.
  - Clarke, Hans Thacher, in re Zyme Dakin
  - Clarke, Hans Thacher, Journal of Biological Chemistry, 1905-1955
  - Clarke, Hans Thacher, Miscellaneous Notes # 1
    [Box 3]
    Speech given at the Annual Meeting of the American Institute of Chemists, N.Y. Chapter, 1954. Personal materials - outline of H.T. Clarke's career and education sent tot eh ACS News Service 1946. Congratulations and awards: Certificate of Merit for service to science during WWII awarded by the OSRD; King's Medal for service in the cause of freedom, 1948. Bioliography of Clarke's up until 1954; and biographical data for the Annual Report of the Dept. of Biochemistry, Yale University, May 1957 (50 pp).
  - Clarke, Hans Thacher, Miscellaneous Notes # 2
  - Clarke, Hans Thacher, Miscellaneous Notes # 3
  - Clarke, Hans Thacher, Personal
    Sahud, Mervyn Allen; Fruton, Joseph S.; Pratt, Richardson; Roayl Institution; Ashwin, D.W.; Fackenthal, Frank Diehl; Drum, Hugh A.; Rappleye, Willard C.; Emery, Alden H.; Frey, Charles N.; [Onant, James = removed to folder: Onant, James B.
  - Clarke, Hans T. Photographs
    See: Tuve, Merle
  - Clarke, Hans Thacher, Speech, May 20, 1954
  - Clarke, Heidi, 1960
    Box 3 3 items, 1960 Personal letters.
  - Clarke, John T, 1952-1967
    Box 3 30 items, 1952-1967 Personal and family letters.
  - Clarke, Liz
  - Clarke, Pogo
  - Clarke, Joseph Thacher
  - Clausen, Mrs. May
  - Cohn, Waldo E, 1956-1959
    Box 3 7 items, 1956-1959
  - Columbia University, McMenamin, Edward B.; Schmitt, Alois E.
  - Conant, James Bryant, 1893-
    McIntosh, Rustin; Smith Arthur Calvert; Berry Frank B.; Adams, Roger.
  - Conner, Thomas
  - Cook, Dorothy Skinner
  - Cooke, Francis
  - Cori, Gerty T
  - Corner, Gayton
  - Cowie, Dean
  - Crena De Iongh, Mrs. Polly
  - Cronkhite, Leonard W, Jr.
  - Cummins, J E
  - Dakin, Henry D. (Zyme), 1931-1950
    Hartley, Sir Percival. Box 3 1 file, 1931-1950 Biographical data on Dakin, 1880-1952 sent to Sir Percival Hartley of the Lister Institute, 1952 to help Hartley write obituary of Dakin. 4 personal cards from Dakin to H.T. Clarke 1931-1950.
    See also: Clarke, H.T. First Dakin Memorial Lecture, in:
  - Dale, Sir Henry Hallett, 1957
    Box 3 1 item, 1957
  - Darby, Eleanor
    DuVigneaud, Vincent.
  - Darrach, William D
  - Davenport College, Yale University
    Liebert, Herman W.; Merriman, Daniel.
  - Davidson, Eugene
  - Davis, Harry
  - Day, Mrs. Ida
  - Deignan, Stella Leche
  - Dickey, J B
  - Dietrich, LeRoy S
    LEwis, George T.; Smith, Sam C.
  - Doering, Willliam
  - Donnan, Frederick George, 1870-
    Drummond, J. C.
  - Drummond, Ann
    Drummond, J C
  - Dutcher, James D
  - Du Vigneaud, Vincent
    See also: American Chemical Society; Darby, Eleanor, in:
    Box 3 Correspondence re: exchange of reprints. Reminiscences of graduate student days with Prof. John R. Murlin at the University of Rochester, 11 pp written by Du Vignaud.
  - Dwyer, Hugh L
  - Eastman Chemical Products, Inc.
  - Eastman, Irene
  - Eastman Kodak Company # 1, 1912-1963
    Leermakers, J. A.; Wynd, Clarence, L. A.; Smith, R. F.; Malm, C. J.; Smith, Jean; Hiatt, Gordon; Genung, Leo B.; Salo, Martti; Brummitt, Wyatt B.
    Box 3 3 files, 1912-1963
    Arrangements for Clarke to visit the Eastman Kodak Laboratories. Letters re: chemicals and chemical preparations. A few letters re: Clarke's work with Eastman Kodak scanning the current literature fro the company and making abstracts.
  - Eastman Kodak Company # 2
    Roll, L. J.; Wynd, Clarence L. A.; Malm, C.J.; WIlliams, Robert F.; Smith, Jean; Brummitt, Wyatt H.
  - Eastman Kodak Company # 3
    Salo, Martti; Clark, Walter; Maloney, L.; Hiatt, Gordon D.; Roll, L. J.; Litten, Walter.
  - Eastman Kodak Patents # 1
    Box 3
  - Eastman Kodak Patents # 2
  - Eberhart, John C
    Heffron, Roderick; Erlander, Bernard F.
  - Eckert, Fritz
  - Eden, Christopher
  - Edsall, John T, 1956-1962
    See also: American Society of Biological Chemists; Journal of Biological Chemistry, in: See also: National Academy of Sciences; Papers Submitted, in:
    Box 4 6 items, 1956-1962
    General correspondence
  - Edwards, Elizabeth
  - Egerton, Sir Alfred
  - Eickelberg, Warren W, 1966-1967
    See also: Adelphi University, in:
    Schmitt, Francis O.
    Box 4 4 items, 1966-1967 Letters, re: arrangements for the Dakin Memorial Lecture, 1967.
  - Eilers, Louis K
  - Eisenhart, M Herbert
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
  - Ellenbogen, Eric
  - Ellis, Lillian N
  - Emerson, Alfred E
  - Emerson, George H
  - Encyclopedia Britannica
  - Endeavour
  - English, Horace B
  - Erlanger, Bernard F, 1960
    See also: Eberhart, John C., in:
    Moe, Henry Allen.
    Box 4 3 letters, 1960 Request from Guggenheim Foundation for Clarke to write a recommendation of Erlanger's work.
  - Evans, B Ifor
  - Evans, Mrs. Joseph C
  - Farber, Sidney, 1961
    Box 4 1 file, 1961 Correspondence, re: exchange of reprints. Farber wrote to Clarke asking Clarke to look over an article for him. Clarke offered a position at the Children's Cancer Research Fund, Inc., 1961.
  - Farinholt, Larkin H
    See also: U.S. State department, in:
  - Fassett, David W
  - Feiler, Marie
  - Fenner, Mrs. Marcella
  - Feuerstein, F J
    Van Deusen, W. P.; Montean, John.
  - Fink, Seymour
  - Fisher, Edward F
  - Fleming, Thomas P
  - Florey, Sir Howard W
  - Fohlin, Birgitta
  - Foote, Paul D, 1957-1958
    See also: Penicillin, in:
    Himsworth, Sir Harold P. Box 4 8 items, 1957-1958 Letters to Clarke, re: patenting rights on production of penicillin developed during WWII on a joint U.K.-U.S. project.
  - Forbes, Anne P
  - Fordyce, Charles R
  - Franklin, Edward C
    See also: Kunkel, Henry, in:
  - Franklin Institute
    Fahrney, D. S.
  - Frazer, Alastair, 1952
  - Freeman, Bromley S
  - Freudenberg, Karl Johann
  - Frieden, Earl
  - Friskin, Mrs. James [Beccle? - Nickname]
  - Fruton, Joseph S, 1955-1972
    See also: Hans T. Clarke Papers
    Heffron, Roderick. Box 4, 7 items, 1955-1972 Notice from Fruton of acceptance by Fred Richards of position at Yale, 1954. Letters, re: Fruton's sabbatical, 1961.
  - Gannett, Mrs. Caroline Werner
  - Genhart, Cecile Staub
  - Genung, Leo B
    See also: Eastman Kodak Company, in:
  - George Eastman House
  - Gies, William J
    Eisenhart, Luther Phaler; Karshan, Maxwell; Kurzrok, Raphael; Kunitz, Moses.
    Box 4, 1 file, Collection of letters from many scientists, re: Gies to use in Clarke's biography of Gies.
  - Goldfarb, A J, 1956
    Box 4 3 items, 1956 Clarke nominated for vice-president of the Society of Experimental Biology & Medicine.
  - Goodhart, Arthur L
  - Gottschall, Gertrude Y
    See also: Tobacco Industry Research Committee, in:
  - Gould, Orin A
  - Greenstein, Jesse P. Memorial Foundation
    Winitz, Milton; Vickery, H. B.
  - Gressley, Gene M
  - Grimm, Beate
  - Guggenheim, John Simon, Memorial Foundation
  - Gwei-Djen
  - Haddow, Alex
  - Halket, Ann C
  - Handler, Philip, 1964
    Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry
    Box 4 2 items, 1964 Clarke asked to be chairman of a session at the 6th International Congress of Biochemistry - declined.
    See also: American Society of Biological Chemists in: See: National Academy of Sciences
  - Hanger, Franklin M
  - Harbury
  - Hardin, Byron, 1962-1969
    Box 4 15 items, 1962-1969 Personal correspondence.
  - Hardy, Harriet L
  - Harrell, George T
  - Harington, Sir Charles R
  - Harris, Joseph
  - Harrow, Benjamin
  - Hartley, Sir Percival
    See also: Dankin, Zyme, in:
  - Harvey, Ash & Co.
    Ash, Maurice E
  - Hawley, Estelle E
  - Heilbron, Sir Ian
  - Helferich, Burkhardt
  - Helferich, Heinrich
  - Hendrick, Ellwood
  - Herbst, Robert M
  - Herstein, Karl M
  - Hiatt, Gordon
  - Hill, A V
    See: table of contents
  - Himsworth, Sir Harold
    See also: Foote, Paul D.; Penicillin, in:
  - Hirs, Mrs. Christopher H W
  - Hitchcock, David Ingersoll, 1893
  - Hobart, Christine L
  - Hoberman, Henry D
  - Hoffman, William F
  - Holden, Reuben A, 1958
    Box 4 2 items, 1958 Letters, re: Clarke's giving XI Lecture at Yale University.
  - Horan, Damarin
  - Horecker, B L
  - Hosmer, James
  - Howell, Stacy F
  - Huff, Robert
  - Hughes, Walter L, 1963
    Box 4 1 items, 1963 ....celebrate Van Slyke's 80th...
  - Hulka, Jaroslav F
  - Hunsaker, Alice P
    Catgut Acoustical Society
  - Hutchins, Carleen M
  - Huxley, Sir Julian Sorell, 1958-1972
    Huxley, Julietta.
    Box 4 17 letters, 1958-1972 Semi-personal and professional correspondence.
  - Institute of International Education, 1957
    Biographical/Historical note
    Box 4 1 item, 1957 Thanks to Clarke for advice given to the Institute on biochemical affairs during 1957.
  - Interscience Publishers Incorporated, 1954
    Box 4 1 letter, 1954 Request for Clarke to edit "Handbook of Biochemistry."
  - James, Henry, 1880-1957
  - Janus, J W
  - Jensen, Mrs. Elizabeth
  - Johnson, John R
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry # 1, 1958-1961
    Karnovsky, Manfred L.; Edsall, John T.; Caputto, Ranwel; Irreverre, Filadelfo; Conn, Eric E.; Weissbach, Herbert; Shimi, Ibrahim Raouf; Hobbs, Donald C.; Bloch, Konrad; Price, J. M.; Lotspeich, F. J.; Bergmann, F.
    Box 4 8 files, 1958-1961 Administrative correspondence. Comments of several members of the Editorical Board on contributions to the Journal. Report of meetings, re: decision whether or not the Journal should re-establish the section of letters to the editor. Report on the activities of the Journal, 1958-60. Notices and minutes of Editorial Board Committee, April 1959. Book of instructions to authors for use in writing articles for the Journal. Summary of the manuscripts acted upon by editors, 1960 - includes a report on the activities of the Journal for 1960.
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry # 2
    Richert, Dan A.; Witkop, Bernard; Edsall, John T.; Roston, Sidney; Lotspeich, F. J.; Sobotka, Harry; Levine, Bernard; Bergmann, F.; Kredich,
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry # 3
    Edsall, John T.; Vickery, H. B.; Meister, Alton.
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry # 4
    Edsall, John T.
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry # 5
    Edsall, John T.; Dunn, Max S.; Mallette, M. F.
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry # 6
    Edsall, John T.; Ratner, Sarah; Hagopian, Miasnig; Witkop, Bernard.
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry # 7
    Heidelberger, Charles; Edsall, John T.; Witkop, Bernard; Cooperman, Jack M.; Henderson, L. M.; Meister, Alton; Price, J. M.; Conn, Eric E.
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry # 8
    Weisburger, John H.; Beyler, R. E.; Edsall, John T.; Johnson, Marvin; Roston, Sidney; Kirshner, Norman; Tanenbaum, Stuart W.; Kuc, Joseph; Schayer, R. W.
  - Kahovec, Jaroslav
  - Kallir, R F
  - Kamen, Martin
  - Karnovsky, Manfred L, 1971
    See also: Journal of Biological Chemistry, in:
    Box 5 1 item, 1971 Letter wishing Clarke well on his retirement, 8/10/1971.
  - Karsham, Maxwell
    See also: Gies, W.J., in:
  - Kassell, Beatrice, 1957
  - Katz, Erika
  - Katz, Siegi, 1961-1963
    Box 5 8 items, 1961-1963 Family letters.
  - Kay, Herbert D, 1956
  - Keitel, Hans George
  - Kendall, Mrs. William Sergeant
  - Kerin, Robert
  - Kilgour, Frederick G
  - Killisch, Dorothee
  - Kim, Soon Won, 1957-1960
    Saz, Arthur K.; Litwach, Gerald; White, Abraham.
    Box 5 11 items, 1957-1960
  - King, Donald
  - Kirk, Grayson
  - Knappenberger, Robert
  - Knutti, Ralph E, 1960
  - Kodak
    Planck, Hildegard.
  - Koepfli, Joseph B, 1951
  - Korwan, Samuel
  - Krauss, Felicitas
  - Krolen (?), F W T
  - Kumar, Somar
  - Lamb, Arthur B, 1932
    Box 5 1 item, 1932 On Lamb being made President of the American Chemical Society.
  - Landsborough Thomson, A
  - Landucci, A
  - Laurini, Peter
  - Lawler, H Claire, 1962
    See also: American Society of Biological Chemists, in:
  - Lehninger, Albert L
  - Leinsdorf, Erich
  - Leppard, Vernon
  - Levine, Julius, 1966-1967
    Box 5 6 items, 1966-1967 Family correspondence.
  - Lewallen, Mrs. Valerie
  - Lewis, George T
    See also: Dietrich, Leroy S., in: See also: University of Miami, in:
  - Lilienfeld, Leon
  - Linderstrom-Lang, Kaj Ulrik, 1896-1959
    3 letters
  - Lindskog, Gustaf E
  - Link, Karl Paul
  - Lippard, Vernon W, 1964
    See also: National Institutes of Health, in:
    Box 5 2 items, 1964 Letters in which Clarke is told he must vacate his laboratories in the Dept. of Biochemistry at Yale Univ. Medical School.
  - Locke, Elizabeth
  - Lockspeiser, Sir Ben
  - Loeb, William
  - Long, Cyril Norman Hugh (1907-1970), 1957
    Box 5 7 items, 1957 Request that Clarke contribute to a volume "A Biochemist's Handbook." - Clarke declined.
  - Long, Esmond Ray
  - Long, Sharon
  - Longmans, Green & Company
  - Loudon, Hughety
  - Love, Robert A
  - Low, Barbara W, 1958-1960
  - Luck, J Murray
    See also: Annual Reviews, Inc., in: See also: Annual Review of Biochemistry, in:
  - Lu Gwei-Djen
  - Lynen, F
  - McCarthy, John
  - McCollester, Duncan L
  - McCormick, James E
  - McGraw-Hill Encyclopedia of Science and Technology
  - McIntosh, Rustin
    See also: Conant, James B., in:
  - McLean, R C
  - McLean and Boustead
  - McMaster University
    Bourns, A N
  - Magoffin, J E
  - Malins, Meta
  - Mallinby, May
  - Malm, Carl J
  - Marenghi, Franz
  - Marrian, Guy F
  - Martin, D C
  - Martin, Robert L
  - Martin, Sylvia, and George
  - Matsuda, Yoko
  - Mattei, Joan
  - Maurer, Mrs. Brigitte
  - Maurer, William S
  - Max, O
  - Mazur, Abraham
  - Mei-Mei, Hsiao
  - Meister, Alton
    See also: Biochemical Preparations; Journal of Biological Chemistry, in:
  - Mellanby, May
  - Meltzer, Philip
    See also: American Otological Society, in:
  - Melville, Donald, 1959
    Wisseman, Charles L. Box 5 1 item, 1959
  - Menday, Mrs. C J
    Fishler, Max
  - Merck and Company.
    Fishler, Max.
  - Merck Fellowships #1, 1956-1957
    Tishler, Max; Lapp, Claude J.; Feger, E. W.; Bronk, Detlev W.; Weiss, Paul
    Box 5 2 files, 1956-1957 Annual report, 1957 Copy of a memorandum, re: the new projected use of funds recommended by the Merck Fellowship Board, March 1957. Minutes of the Merck Senior Postdoctoral Fellowship Board, March 1957. Copy of a letter from Warren Weaver to A.N. Richards on problems of how to distribute the Merck Fellowships, Dec. 14, 1956. Letter to Clarke from Kenneth B. Raper, re: Weaver's ideas on the merck Fellowships.
  - Merck Fellowships #2
    Weiss, David W.; Lapp, Claude J.; Weiss, Paul; Cori, Carl F. (1984); Ronkin, R. R. Raper, Kenneth B.; Johnstone, Henry W.
  - Merriman, Daniel, 1964
    Box 5 1 item, 1964 Concerning Davenport College,Yale University.
  - Middleton, Mrs. Dora Clarke #1, 1960-1968
    Box 5 80 items, 1960-1968. Family correspondence.
  - Middleton, Mrs. Dora Clarke #2
  - Middleton, E A
  - Middleton, Gervaise B
  - Minty, Dorothy
  - Mocsanyi, Paul
  - Moe, Henry Allen (1894-), 1963
    See also: American Philosophical Society; Erlander, Barnard F.; Guggenheim, John Simon, Memorial Foundation, in:
    Box 5 3 items, 1963
  - Molitor, Hans
    See also: Journal of Experimental Medicine - Robinson, Harry J., in:
  - Moncreiff, Robert P
  - Mont, Angelika De
  - Moore, Stanford
  - Mukle, May
  - Muntwyler, Edward
  - Nachmansohn, David, (1917), 1961-1969
    Box 5 10 items, 1061-1969. Copy of an article by Nachmansohn 'Die Wissenschaftter Deren Andenken Das Institut fuer Lebenswissenschaftem in Rehovoth Gewidmet ist' - 39 pp. Some personal letters.
  - Nadel, Maxine Alice
    Hildenbrand, Frieda.
  - Nagy, Stephen M, 1957-1964
    Box 5 35 items, 1957-1964 Applications from Clarke to Nagy for chemical analyses to be done in Nagy's laboratory at M.I. T.
  - Nakatani, Misako
  - National Academy of Sciences #1, 1942-1963
    Edsall, John T. BOX 6 3 filess, 1942-1963
    Vitas of applicants for membership to the NAS. Minutes of the business section of the NAS at the 1963 Annual Meeting. Copy of the testimony prepared by Philip Handler give to the House of Representatives Subcommittee on Science Research and Development concerning the appropriation of funds to the National Science Foundation, 30 pp.
    Vigneaud, Vincent du: See also: National Academy of Sciences, in:
  - National Academy of Sciences #2
    Carter, H. E.: See also: National Academy of Sciences; President's Committee on the National Medal of Science, in:
    Carter, H. E.
  - National Academy of Sciences #3
    Handler, Philip; Richards, Alfred Newton, 1876-1966.
  - National Foundation
    O'Conner, Basil.
  - National Institutes of Health, 1957-1963
    Grossnickle, Thurman, T.; Ganz, Aaron; Rivera, Jose A.; Lippard, Vernon W.; Michalski, Josephn V.; Benedict, Jean D.; Pratt, James W.; Ferguson, Frederick P.; Scantlebury, Ronald E.
    Box 6 c. 30 items, 1957-1963 Correspondence, re: references for grant applicants.
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1958
    Miner, Eunice Thomas.
    Box, 1 item, 1958 Clarke's resignation from the Society.
  - No, R Lorente De
    Waelsch, Heinrich.
  - Noller, Carl R
  - Nystrom, Viola
  - Ochoa, Severo
    See also: Nobel Prize - O, in:
  - O'Connor, Basil
  - Organic Synthesis #1, 1950-1962
    McKusick, Blaine C.; Newman, Melvin S.
    Box 6, 3 files, 1950-1962. Correspondence and minutes of the Advisory Board.
  - Organic Synthesis #2
    Arnold, Richard T.; Rabjohn, Norman; Horning, Evan C.
  - Organic Synthesis #3
  - Osborne, Margaret
  - Palmer, John W
  - Papers Submitted
    Coleman, George H.; Edsall, John T.
  - Pappenheimer, John R
    See also: Nobel Prize - P-Q, in:
  - Park, C R
  - Parker, Barrett, 1952
    Box 6 1 items, 1952
    Copy of a letter from Parker to Lord Cherwell (House of Lords), re: the U.S. Embassy's interest in the application of science to economy and industry in Great Britain, 1952.
  - Patents
  - Pearlman, William H
  - Pearson, Karl, 1857-1936
  - Penicillin, 1959-1960
    Johnson, Alfred R.; Sayre, N.; Sheehan, John C[lark]; Princeton Unversity Press; Himsworth, H. P.; Foote, P. D.; York, Herbert F.; Macauly, J. B.
    Box 6 15 Items, 1959-1960.
    Leters, re: the Upjohn and Eli Lilly discoveries of methods of penicillin production during WWII - argument of professional ethics.
  - Perlmann, Gertrude E
  - Perry, Jean
  - Peters, Rudolph A
  - Peters, Theodore, Jr.
  - Peyes, Edith De
  - Pincus, Gregory
  - Planck, Erwin
    Muhle, Hans.
  - Planck, Frida
  - Planckhaus (G.J.)
  - Popkin, Susan L
  - Potter, John V
  - Powell, Monica
  - President's Committee on the National Medal of Science, 1966
    Box 6 1 items, 1966. Request for Clarke to participate in nomination of a candidate, 1966.
  - Princeton University Press
  - Putterman, Gerald J
  - Quarterly Journal: Alcohol, 1957-1962
    Keller, Mark; Haggard, Howard W.
    Box 6 c. 60 items, 1957-1962. Correspondence, re: referee reports and articles to be refereed.
  - Rabinowitch, Eugene
    Forbes, W. H.
  - Rajasthan, University of
    Singhal, C. L.; Varma, K. L.
  - Ranke, Hermann
  - Rappleye, Willard C
  - Ratner, Sarah
  - Rau, Leo
  - Raymond, Samuel
  - Rice, Helen
  - Richards, Heidi, 1960-1967
    Box 6 c. 30 items, 1960-1967. Family correspondence.
  - Richards, Marianna
  - Richards, Mrs. Pauline
  - Richter, George A
  - Richter, Werner
  - Rittenberg, David
  - Robinson, Sir Robert, 1949-1965
    See: Table of Contents to 509:L56.45 Letters of Scientists
    Box 6 11 items, 1949-1965. General correspondence.
  - Roos, Hans
  - Rothschild, Joel
  - Rothschild, Robert F
  - Royal Institute of Chemistry (London), 1959
    Ellingham, H. J. T.
    Box 6 1 item, 1959. Clarke's 50th year as a member of the Society.
  - Rurey, Mrs. Melina
  - Ruttenberg, Michael
  - Sage, Harvey J
  - Salcedo, Juan, Jr.
  - Salisbury, Sir Edward J
    See also: Royal Society of London, in:
  - Schenlabs Pharmaceuticals, Inc.
    Straus, WIlliam T.
  - Schmitt, Francis Otto, 1903-
    See also: Eickelberg, Warren W., in:
  - Science, 1958-1965
    See also: Abelson, Philip H., in: Du Shane, Graham: See: Science, in:
    Abelson, Philip H.; Turner, Joseph; Kozai, Yukie; Du Shane, Graham.
    Box 6 4 items, 1958-1965. Letters asking Clarke to be a reviewer of articles.
  - Segal, Evelyn
  - Seidel, Hildegard
  - Sheehan, John Clark
    See also: Adelphi University; Penicillin, in:
  - Sheldon, Emma Lyon
  - Shepard, Robert A
  - Shockley, William #1, 1968-1970
    Box 6 2 files, 1968-1970. Letter sent to members of NAS who were to attend the business meeting, 4/28/1970 concerning Shockley's application to the NAS for funds to conduct research in eugenics along the lines of Jensen's work.
    Eugenics
  - Shockley, William #2
  - Shrigley, E W, 1957
    Box 6 3 items, 1957.
  - Shrivastava, K C
    See also: Journal of Experimental Medicine - Heidelberger, Michael, in:
  - Simonds, Herbert R
    1 item.
  - Simonsen, J L
  - Simpson, Esther
  - Simpson, Richard B.
  - Skinner, Dorothy